Tom Hooper



linkedin.com/in/tjhooper88



https://tomhoopermedia.netlify.app/



tomh386@gmail.com



386-682-8154

Summary

I'm a self-taught software developer. With a total of 4 years of development experience and over one year of professional experience. My most relevant skill is javascript and React.js. I also use Python for backend REST APIs and machine learning practice.

I constantly stay learning and keeping up with new technologies. I'm currently learning DENO and different ways to utilize python.

Experience



Covid-19 Global Hackathon

Devpost

Mar 2020 - Mar 2020 (1 month)

I participated in a hackathon during the beginning of the Covid-19 pandemic. I teamed up with some great people to build an application that would connect wholesale distributors with local vendors to help move supply that has been interrupted by the broken logistics chain.

I took care of the React front end. I scaffolded out a file architecture and setup the github repository. I used Material UI for quick UI ideas.

Link to the hackathon project: https://devpost.com/software/getbread GitHub: https://github.com/tjhooper1/Unused-Wholesale-Food-Redistribution-? organization=tjhooper1&organization=tjhooper1

Software Developer

Beachfront

Jun 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

I Work on a variety of tasks that include frontend, backend, and creating miscellaneous services. Frontend tooling includes Node.js, React.js and the various libraries commonly used.

I occasionally would make different API endpoints and services in a Java backend as well.

My greatest accomplishment was creating an internal tool used for reporting. I did this with a React frontend and a Node.js backend that communicated with another internal API for stats.

■ Customer Service Team Lead

Publix

2017 - 2018 (2 years)

I managed the frontend team and coordinated tasks to service associates. It was also my responsibility to perform payroll and new hire paperwork. I would occasionally take on extra special campaign projects that the store would participate in.

Education

■ Team TreeHouse

full stack web development

(A) freeCodeCamp

full stack web development certification, Computer Software Engineering 2017 - 2018

II Udemy

Full Stack Web Development

Licenses & Certifications

- The Complete Web Developer in 2018: Zero To Mastery Udemy
- Javascript Basi HackerRank
 BA07DCDEB771
- Python Basic HackerRank 7B2517DE96D1
- Creating Python APIs Like a BOSS The Django REST Framework Udemy UC-789f3849-a570-4903-a4e4-356a45655c06

Skills

JavaScript • React.js • Node.js • Responsive Web Design • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Bootstrap • MongoDB • HTML5 • Python (Programming Language)